AANAND RAMESH

DELIVERY MANAGEMENT, DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION, PRODUCT MANAGEMENT, CUSTOMER EXPERIENCE TOTAL EXPERIENCE

RECENT TECHNOLOGIES:
CLOUD: SFDC (SALES CLOUD,
SERVICE CLOUD, COMMUNITY
CLOUD), SAP FOR OPERATIONS, AWS,
AZURE
DIGITAL: AEM, BLOCKCHAIN
DEVSECOPS, TEST AUTOMATION,
GPT3 (LEGACY MODERNISATION)

HIGHLIGHTS

- ~20 years of experience providing advisory services and implementing solutions
- Product, Portfolio, P&L, Delivery
- Certified SAFe® Agilist (Leading SAFe®)
- Deal management with contract wins worth 45M USD as part of Cognizant.

CONTACT DETAILS

+91 7899831155 aanand.ramesh@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/aanandramesh

EDUCATION

Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering.

Bachelors of Engineering, 2004. Electronics & Communication with consistent 70+ scores

PROFILE SUMMARY

Experienced in product management, Total Experience (TX), customer experience management (CXM), & digital transformation, advising B2B and B2C clients in consumer goods, manufacturing, logistics and utilities industries. Positioned at the intersection of business and technology to enable clients at all levels to realise IT and business strategy across geographies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ITC Infotech Ltd - General Manager - Delivery 03-2022 - Present

Delivery management, transition, transformation, P&L for key accounts

- Delivery, P&L for Whitbread's Digital Engineering teams on AEM stacks using SAFe, Implemented Total Experience solution through program and process structuring
- Global transition and transformation director for British American Tobacco, transitioned 400+ team across 5 locations, 10 vendors, 18+ tech stacks. Transformed multiple tracks to SAFe® Essential config
- Implementation and delivery management (6 new implementations) for custom B2B field sales product with 10000 users in 65 countries (exceeded P&L target by 20%)

Infosys Technologies Ltd - Principal Consultant 08-2021 - 03-2022

Product Management

- Provided product vision, and roadmap to three products on DevSecOps, Code Migration, and Test Automation
- Lead GTM activities for three products Blog on security in DevSecOps, Whitepaper on DevSecOps

Neural Rays AI Ltd - Senior Product Manager 11-2020 - 08-2021

Product Management and Leadership

 Realised product and platform vision for Solve.Care and launching multiple services on their blockchain - cryptocurrency platform

Cognizant Technology Solutions Ltd. - Manager 05-2008 - 11-2020

Product & Program management | Agile delivery

- Implemented annual release of CPLM (Windchill) for Philips using Scaled Agile framework
- Rolled out SalesForceHR using Scrum for Unilever (integrating Workday, Remedy) as part of global talent acquisition and talent management processes.
- Implemented SFDC for Cargill in agile scrum. On-boarded multiple regions on to SalesCloud, ServiceCloud, and CommunityCloud (B2B).
- Introduced self-serve options to pre-pay smart meter customers for British Gas (iOS, Android).

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Infosys Technologies Ltd Programmer Analyst 07-2004 - 04-2008

- Led team of cross-functional technology experts to engage regional heads of IT of world's largest electronics distribution company towards realising IT goals in 20+ countries.
- Engaged NR Narayana Murthy, President of Infosys Technologies Solutions and Prof Amitava Bannerjee of Indian Statistical Institute to identify trends in defect occurrence and recommend strategy to reduce defect incidence in IT lifecycle.

24/7 Customer Pvt Ltd. Exec - Tech Support 09-2003 - 03-2004

 Led a team of technology experts providing technology support to SOHO users in the USA for the world's largest OS manufacturer.
 Point of contact for "hot escalations" tasked with improving customer experience and solving issues of high complexity Developed and led implementation of omni-channel selfserve capabilities for large landlords unit of British Gas reducing costs (personnel, operational). Improved communications workflows reduced operating costs by GBP100,000 p.a.

${\bf Business\ advisory\ | Transformation}$

Internal

- Led operational change management, strategy definition & implementation for Cognizant's new business venture on large scale digital and business transformation
- Developed key elements of Cognizant's strategy for service lines and new geographies for senior VPs and head of corporate strategy as part of corporate strategy team

Clients

- Recommended changes to business operations for British Gas to enable them to be first in market to install SMETS2 smart meters
- Helped shape overall business direction on digital strategy for B2B unit of British Gas and won multiple awards including "Best website" B2B Marketing awards, high commendation for "Best website" at the Rev Digital awards, Winner - "Customer Services Innovation" - European Smart Meter Awards
- Enabled globalization and localisation of warranty management systems for region head of warranty management of Toyota Motor Sales bringing together dealers (1000+) in USA, CAN and Mexico
- Advised CIO of Payless Shoesource on defining strategy and implementation to create a QA centre of excellence supporting 40+ members in a global setup
- Recommended changes to identity and access management of B2B users of A.P Moller Maersk towards implementing omnichannel customer engagement

Intellectual property creation

- Developed ready deployable product for customer sales and self-service for Cognizant's Utilities Customer Experience Management Practice. Won implementation at leading water utility in the UK
- Derived workflows and process models to develop Cognizant's Automobile Warranty Management solution: Warranty Information System for Analytics, Reporting and Decisionmaking (WISARD)®

Technology | Process advisory

- Defined workflows to ensure the first implementation of EnerNoc's Pulse Energy® analytics platform for British Gas
- Developed QA offshoring strategy for Head of Quality Assurance for ING Insurance USA to transition to a global delivery setup generating 1+M USD of revenue

Sales solutions management

- Solution architect for a new account in consumer goods practice win as part of a 37M USD 3 year relationship for providing QA services
- Led a team of solution architects on a 3M USD deal for implementing IT systems for demerger / spin off of a large process manufacturing customer